In lesson one, we'll
be covering models, prompts, and
parsers. So models refers to the
language models underpinning a
lot of it. Prompts refers to
the style of creating inputs
to pass into the models.
And then parsers is
on the opposite end.
It involves taking the
output of these models
and parsing it into
a more structured format
so that you can
do things downstream with it.
Yep, so when you build
an application using LLM, there'll
often be reusable models. We
repeatedly prompt a model, parses
outputs, and so LangChain gives
an easy set of abstractions to
do this type of operation.
So with that, let's
jump in and take a look at models, prompts,
and parsers.
So to get started, here's
a little bit of starter code. I'm going
to import OS, import OpenAI, and load
my OpenAI secret key. The OpenAI
library is already
installed in my Jupyter Notebook environment.
If you're running this
locally, and you don't
have OpenAI installed
yet, you might need to
run that. Bang, pip install OpenAI, but
I'm not going to do
that here.
And then here's a helper function. This
is actually very similar to the
helper function that you might have
seen in the ChaiGPT prompt engineering
for developers course
that I offered together with OpenAI's
Iza Fulford. And so, with this
helper function, you can
say get completion on what
is 1 plus 1, and this
will call ChatGPT, or technically
the model, GPT 3.5 Turbo, to
give you
an answer back like this.
Now, to motivate the
line chain abstractions
for model prompts and parsers, let's
say you get an email
from a customer in a
language other than English.
In order to make
sure this is accessible,
the other language I'm going to use is
the English pirate language, where
the consists are, I'd be
fuming that me blender
lid flew off and
splattered my kitchen walls
with smoothie.
And to make matters worse,
the warranty don't cover the cost of
cleaning up me kitchen. I
need your help right now, matey.
And so, what we will do is,
ask this LLM to
translate the text to
American English in a
calm and respectful tone. So I'm
going to set style
to American English in
a calm and respectful tone. And
so, in
order to actually accomplish this, if
you've seen a little bit of
prompting before,
I'm going to specify the
prompt using an f-string with
the instructions, translate the
text that is
delimited by triple
backticks into style that is style,
and then
plug in these two styles.
And so, this generates a prompt
that says translate the
text and so on.
I encourage you to pause
the video and run the code,
and also try modifying the
prompt to see if you
can get a different output.
You can then
prompt the Large Language
Model to get a response. Let's
see what the response is. Says
translated the English pirate's message
into this very polite, I'm really frustrated
that my blender lid
flew off and made a mess of my
kitchen walls with smoothie
and so on.
I could really use your help right now,
my friend.
That sounds very nice.
So, if you have
different customers writing
reviews in different languages,
not just English pirate, but French,
German, Japanese, and so on,
you can imagine having to generate
a whole sequence of prompts to
generate such translations. Let's
look at how we can do
this in a more convenient, way
using LangChain. I'm going
to import chat OpenAI. This is
LangChain's abstraction for
the chatGPT API endpoint.
And so, if I then set
chat equals chat OpenAI
and look at what chat is,
it creates this object as follows
that uses the chatGPT model,
which is also called GPT 3.5 turbo.
When I'm building applications, one
thing I will often do
is set the temperature parameter
to be equal to zero. So
the default temperature is 0.7.
But let me actually
redo that with temperature
equals 0.0, and now the temperature is
set to 0 to make this output a
little bit less random.
And now, let me define the
template string as follows.
Translate the text delimited
by triple vectors into
style that is style, and then here's
the text. And
to repeatedly reuse this template, let's
import
LangChain's chat prompt template,
and then, let me create
a prompt template
using that template string that we
just wrote above.
From the prompt template,
you can actually
extract the original prompt,
and it realizes that this
prompt has two input variables,
the style and the text,
which were shown here
with the curly braces.
And here is the
original template as well
that we had specified.
In fact, if I print this out,
it realizes it has two input variables,
style and text. Now, let's
specify the style. This is a style that
I want the customer
message to be translated
to, so I'm going
to call this customer style,
and here's my
same customer email
as before. And now,
if I create customer messages,
his will generate the prompt,
and will pass this
large language model in
a minute to get a response.
So if you want to look at the types,
the customer message is actually a
list,
and if you look at
the first element of the list,
this is more or less
that prompt that you would
expect this to be creating.
Lastly, let's
pass this prompt to the LLM, so I'm going
to call chat, which we
had set earlier,
as a reference to
the OpenAI chatGPT endpoint,
and, if we print out
the customer responses content,
then, it gives you back this text
translated from English
pirate to polite American English.
And of course, you can imagine other
use cases where the
customer emails are in
other languages and this
too can be used
to translate the messages
for an English-speaking
to understand and reply to.
I encourage you to
pause the video and
run the code and also
try modifying the prompt
to see if you can get a different
output.
Now let's hope our customer
service agent replies
to the customer in their original
language. So let's say,
English-speaking
customer service agent writes
this and says, "Hey
there customer, warranty
does not cover
cleaning expenses for
your kitchen because it's your
fault. You misused
your blender by forgetting to
put on the lid. Tough luck.
See ya."
Now they're polite message, but
let's say this is what a
customer service agent wants.
We are going to specify
that the service message
is going to be
translated to this pirate style.
So we want it to
be in a polite tone that speaks in
English pirate.
And because we previously
created that prompt template,
the cool thing is, we can now reuse
that prompt template and
specify that the output
style we want is
this service style pirate
and the text is this service reply.
And if we do that,
that's the prompt.
And if we prompt,
ChaiGPT,
this is the response it gives us back.
"Ahoy there, matey!
I must kindly inform you
that the warranty be
not covering the expenses
or cleaning your galley."
And so on. Aye, tough luck.
Farewell, me hearty.
So, you might be wondering,
why are we using
prompt templates instead of,
you know, just an f-string? The
answer is that as
you build sophisticated applications,
prompts
can be quite long and detailed.
And so, prompt templates are
a useful abstraction to help you
reuse good prompts when you can.
This is an example
of a relatively long
prompt to grade a student's
submission
for an online learning application.
And a prompt like this can be quite
long, in which you can ask the
LLM to first solve the problem,
and then have the
output in a certain format,
and the output in a certain format.
And wrapping this in
a LangChain prompt makes
it easier to reuse
a prompt like this.
Also, you see later
that LangChain provides
prompts for some common operations,
such as summarization, or
question answering,
or connecting to SQL databases,
or connecting to different APIs.
And so by using some of LangChain's
built-in prompts, you can quickly get an
application working without
needing to,
engineer your own prompts.
One other aspect of LangChain's
prompt libraries
is that it also supports output parsing,
which we'll get to in a minute.
But when you're building a complex application
using an LLM,
you often instruct the LLM
to generate its output
in a certain format,
such as using specific keywords.
This example on
the left illustrates using an LLM
to carry out something called chain
of thought reasoning
using a framework called the React
framework. But don't
worry about the technical details, but
the keys of that is that
the thought is what the LLM
is thinking,
because by giving an LLM space to think,
it can often get
to more accurate conclusions.
Then action as a keyword
to carry the specific action,
and then observation to show what
it learned from that action,
and so on.
And if you have a
prompt that instructs the LLM
to use these specific keywords,
thought, action, and observation,
then this prompt can
be coupled with a parser
to extract out the
text that has been
tagged with these specific keywords.
And so that together
gives a very nice
abstraction to specify the
input to an LLM,
and then also have
a parser correctly interpret
the output that the LLM gives.
And so with that, let's
return to see an example of an output
parser using LangChain.
In this example, let's
take a look at how you can have
an LLM output JSON,
and use LangChain to parse that output.
And the running example that I'll
use will be
to extract
information from a product review,
and format that output in a JSON format.
So here's an example of how
you would like the output to be formatted.
Technically,
this is a Python dictionary,
where whether or not
the product is a gift,
maps to false,
the number of days it
took to deliver was five,
and the price value was pretty
affordable.
So this is one example of a desired
output,
here is an example
of customer review, as well as a
template to try to get to that JSON
output.
So here's a customer review. It
says, this
lead blower is pretty amazing. It
has four settings, candle blower, gender
breeze, windy city, and
tornado.
It arrived in two days,
just in time for my wife's
anniversary present. I
think my wife liked it
so much she was speechless. So
far, I've been
the only one using it, and so
on. And here's a review
template. For the following
text, extract the following
information.
Specify, was this a gift?
So in this case, it would be yes,
because this is a gift.
And also, delivery days.
How long did it take to deliver?
It looks like in this case,
it arrived in two days.
And what's the price value? You
know, slightly more expensive than
the lead blowers, and so on. So,
the
review template asks the LLM
to take as input a customer review
and extract
these three fields and then
format the output as JSON
with the following keys.
All right. So here's
how you can wrap this in
LangChain. Let's
import the chat prompt template. We'd
actually imported this already
earlier. So technically,
this line
is redundant, but I'll just import
it again and then
have the prompt templates
created from
the review template
up on top.
And so, here's the prompt template.
And now, similar to our earlier
usage of a prompt template, let's
create the
messages to pass to the
OpenAI,
endpoint.
Create the OpenAI endpoint,
call that endpoint, and then let's
print out the response.
I encourage you to pause
the video and run the code.
And there it is. It says,
give us true, delivery day is 2,
and the price value also looks
pretty accurate. But note that if we
check the type
of the response,
this is actually a string.
So it looks like JSON
and looks like it has key-value
pairs, but it's actually
not a dictionary. This is
just
one long string.
So what I'd really like to do
is go to the
response content and get
the value from the
gift key which should be true, but
I run this, this
should generate an error
because, well,
this is actually a string.
This is not a Python dictionary. So,
let's
see how we will use LangChain's parser
in order to do this. I'm going to
import response schema and
structured output parser from
LangChain.
And I'm going to tell it what
I wanted to parse by
specifying these response schemas. So
the gif schema is named gif, and
here's the description. Was the
item purchased as a gift
for someone else?
Answer true or yes,
false if not or unknown, and so on.
So, have a gift schema,
delivery date schema,
price value schema, and then let's
put all three of them into a list
as follows.
Now that I've specified the schema for
these LangChain can actually
give you the prompt
itself by
having the output parser tell you
what instructions it wants you
to send to the LLM.
So if I were to print
format instructions.
She has a pretty precise set
of instructions for the LLM that
will cause it to generate an
output that the output parser
can process.
So here's the new review template,
and the review
template includes the
format instructions that LangChain
generated.
And so we can create a prompt
from the review template too,
and then create the
messages that will pass
to the OpenAI endpoint.
If you want, you can take a
look at the actual prompt,
which gives the instructions to extract
the fields gift, delivery days,
price value,
here's the text,
and then here are the formatting
instructions.
Finally, if we
call the OpenAI
endpoint,
let's
take a look at what response we got.
It is now this,
and now if we use
the output parser that we created
earlier,
you can then parse
this into an output dictionary,
which if I print, looks like this.
And notice that this is
of type dictionary, not a string,
which is why I can
now extract the value
associated with the key
gift and get true, or
the value associated with delivery days
and get two,
or you can also extract the
value associated with price value.
So this is a nifty way to
take your LLM output and parse it
into a Python dictionary,
to make the output easier
to use in downstream processing.
I encourage you to pause
the video and run the code.
And so, that's it for models, prompts,
and parsers. With
these tools, hopefully you'll be
able to
reuse your own prompt templates easily,
share prompt templates
with others that you're
collaborating with, even
use LangChain's built-in prompt templates,
which as you
just saw, can often be
coupled with an output
parser,
so that the input prompt to output
in a specific format
and then the parser,
parses that output to store the
data in a Python dictionary or
some other data
structure that makes it easy for
downstream processing.
I hope you find this
useful in many of your applications.
And with that, let's
go into the next video where we'll see
how LangChain can help you
build better chatbots, or have
an LLM have more effective chats
by better managing
what it remembers
from the conversation
you've had so far.